<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Terry Lansdown</title>
	<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts"/>
	<updated>2016-05-26T18:07:12+01:00</updated>
	<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts</id>
	<author>
		<name>Terry Lansdown</name>
		<email>terry@lansdown.me</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Hold Fire...</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/10/22/hold-fire"/>
			<updated>2012-10-22T17:13:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/10/22/hold-fire</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;…Just too busy with work stuff to add much here. Back to it soon[ish].&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Manifesto for a Playing Time Equivalent</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/06/04/manifesto-for-playing-time-equivalent"/>
			<updated>2012-06-04T11:30:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/06/04/manifesto-for-playing-time-equivalent</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reflecting on an interesting discussion on &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze/79&quot;&gt;Build and Analyse 79&lt;/a&gt; about equivalence on Freemium games. You know the situation, you would like some more colours, or a big gun to enrich your game playing experience. You can buy these as in application purchases, or you can play the game to &#39;earn&#39; them. A game designer has, at least, three choices when modelling the gameplay:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;give it all away, nice, but presumably doesn&#39;t pay their rent&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;gouge you by making you play for a million years to earn your &#39;treats&#39;, or&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;tread the delicate line between effort and reward that leads to rewarding game play.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about we all lobby for a standardised unit of comparison, so we can work out the cost per hour. A Playing Time Equivalent (PTE) so we can make our own judgments about whether our time is worth the rewards on offer. This raises a broader question about what we get out of these games. On &lt;a href=&quot;http://twit.tv/show/this-week-in-tech/355&quot;&gt;TWIT&lt;/a&gt;, Diablo 3 was discussed as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operant_conditioning_chamber&quot;&gt;Skinner Box&lt;/a&gt;. This rang very true to me. You ever played a game for a few hours, and Minecraft springs to mind here, achieved some trivial goal, then wondered how that takes your life forward? As a relaxing recreation, great, but if I stop to think about my PTE in the real world, ah, er, oh…pass the controller.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Android on iPhone</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/04/23/android-on-iphone"/>
			<updated>2012-04-23T13:54:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/04/23/android-on-iphone</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be interesting if we could run Android or iOS on reference hardware, a-la, the x86 desktop processor? I wonder if Apple would sell many iPhones for people to install Android onto the hardware? There seems to be a good number of people running Windows on Apple/Intel hardware. Good or bad for mobile platform development if we had standardised hardware? Wouldn’t it be nice to choose the hardware for the OS you prefer. Of course, some might not wish to allow their OS to function with other hardware, HackiPhone anyone?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Best Wishes or Thanks for Email Signatures?</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/04/17/best-wishes-or-thanks-for-email"/>
			<updated>2012-04-17T13:44:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/04/17/best-wishes-or-thanks-for-email</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I routinely sign off my emails with…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Best wishes,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Terry”&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;But often I’m saying thanks rather than wishing recipients all the very best. So, what do I do? I use an AppleScript wrapped in a TextExpander snippet. Here’s the text from the AppleScript, if it helps anyone. Easy and simple, but it deletes the previous sign-off as well as replacing it with the text I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;tell application &quot;System Events&quot;&lt;br /&gt;key code 123 -- left arrow&lt;br /&gt;key code 123 -- left arrow			&lt;br /&gt;key down shift&lt;br /&gt;key code 125 -- down arrow&lt;br /&gt;key code 125 -- down arrow&lt;br /&gt;key code 125 -- down arrow&lt;br /&gt;key code 125 -- down arrow&lt;br /&gt;key up shift&lt;br /&gt;key code 117 -- Delete&lt;br /&gt;Keystroke return&lt;br /&gt;Keystroke return&lt;br /&gt;Keystroke &quot;Thanks,&quot;&lt;br /&gt;Keystroke return&lt;br /&gt;Keystroke return&lt;br /&gt;Keystroke &quot;Terry&quot;&lt;br /&gt;Keystroke return&lt;br /&gt;end tell&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Disable the File Extension Change Warning in Mac OS X</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/04/12/disable-file-extension-change-warning"/>
			<updated>2012-04-12T14:22:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/04/12/disable-file-extension-change-warning</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another great little tweak to make life easier:&lt;br /&gt; “defaults write com.apple.finder FXEnableExtensionChangeWarning -bool false”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://osxdaily.com/2012/04/11/disable-the-file-extension-change-warning-in-mac-os-x/&quot;&gt;OSX Daily&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>The Watchmaker</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/04/02/watchmaker"/>
			<updated>2012-04-02T14:13:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/04/02/watchmaker</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just great. via &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.makezine.com/2012/04/02/the-watchmaker/watchmaker/&quot;&gt;MAKE&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Make your Library visible</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/03/06/make-your-library-visible"/>
			<updated>2012-03-06T13:27:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/03/06/make-your-library-visible</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bringing it back to how you want it, to re-enable visibility of the Library. In the terminal on OSX Lion:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;chflags nohidden ~/Library&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;(from &lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/&quot;&gt;inessential.com&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Ruminations on 'Right vs. Pragmatic'</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/03/01/ruminations-on-vs-pragmatic"/>
			<updated>2012-03-01T14:49:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/03/01/ruminations-on-vs-pragmatic</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marco Arment&amp;#8217;s recent post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marco.org/2012/02/25/right-vs-pragmatic&quot;&gt;&amp;#8216;Right vs Pragmatic&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; inspired some thoughts in the in me as jobbing ergonomist. He uses an example I&amp;#8217;ve used before to illustrate some interesting behaviours concerning design, hygiene, and maintenance. Okay, four sacred principles of ergonomic design are to consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;frequency of use&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;importance of use&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;sequences of action, and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;grouping of related items.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marco illustrates nicely the consequences of failing to consider these principles using a men&amp;#8217;s bathroom. The many of the users don&amp;#8217;t want to touch the handle so they use and drop paper towels on the floor next to it. Incidentally, blokes will know the uncomfortable feeling of seeing someone not wash their hands and leave, and then discovering a wet door handle from the previous hand-washing user, hopefully, maybe not, nasty. Shame on you, if you don&#39;t wash. He mentions some solutions, from the passive-aggressive notices to moving the waste-bin. When the users drop towels, they are clues that the design is flawed. I can see where he&#39;s coming from in adopting a quick pragmatic fix, as a general solution. However, lets step back and consider the source of the problem. The vast majority of men&amp;#8217;s rooms, have a handle on the inside. Why, handles say pull. Flat plates say push, why not use them on the inside of the door? This also facilitates use of other parts of the door to leave the room. By stepping back and designing the environment initially with consideration for user behaviour, the clumsy retrospective solutions could be avoided. It doesn&#39;t take long to switch a handle to a plate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Danger: Rant - iTunes Match not Good on Slow Connections</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/03/01/itunes-match-not-good-on-slow"/>
			<updated>2012-03-01T09:06:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/03/01/itunes-match-not-good-on-slow</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My experience of iTunes Match on my slow rural broadband is not good, when bandwidth is tight, i.e., always. When I select a track to stream (well download really), iTunes will fail and skip to the next track; then fail, skip to the next track; then…err…fail and skip the next track. Clearly, its comparing download speeds with playback and giving up. Jumping to the next track just isn’t the behaviour I’m expecting, and it resets the problem, nnngh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Update: Actually, calmed down a bit now, general performance is good, but when the ‘small pipe’ is under stress, it fails badly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>There's no issue with Apple cables getting tangled</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/02/15/there-no-issue-with-apple-cables"/>
			<updated>2012-02-15T14:33:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/02/15/there-no-issue-with-apple-cables</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/t.c.lansdown/IfYouVeGotAThinGripDonTHangAbout?authkey=Gv1sRgCLu5hpP8hY69FQ#5709370460076661490&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-yVR7EdjISGY/TzvCLxP6WvI/AAAAAAAAAUA/qJx9OnZixwI/s288/0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; style=&quot;margin:5px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>iBooks - for everyone?</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/01/20/ibooks-for-everyone"/>
			<updated>2012-01-20T17:35:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/01/20/ibooks-for-everyone</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pretty as the iBooks are, assuming you are happy with the default options. Its not going to happen, but it would be rather nice if there were tools to use iBooks books on the Mac, PC, iPhone, other devices too. Even the Kindle, if some financial and export mechanism could be determined. Industry standards anyone? Not a lot of uptake so far for FaceTime by other software and devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>The State of the iPad Competition - a Consumer View</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2012/01/08/state-of-ipad-competition-consumer-view"/>
			<updated>2012-01-08T10:29:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2012/01/08/state-of-ipad-competition-consumer-view</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had a bit of idle time with the family in the shops. Decided to take a look at the current state of tablets. Disclaimer: I&amp;#8217;m an iPad user since day one. Tried a few options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Arnova 8&amp;quot; G2 - buttons designed for portrait, display defaults to portrait. Rotated the display thinking that it would flip, no luck. Did a bit of &amp;#8216;bouncing&amp;#8217; it up and down, no luck. Walked away.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MOTOROLA Xoom - couldn&amp;#8217;t find the on button, I think, (and online searching suggests) its on the back, but the only likely candidate had a unlock padlock icon and didn&amp;#8217;t work to switch the device on. Hunted for several minutes&amp;#8230;and walked away.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;BLACKBERRY PlayBook - blank screen. Now, starting to expect this, I dug around for the power button. I was surprised to see it was a tiny 2&amp;#8211;3mm button on the top, slightly to the left of the centre of the device in portrait mode. Pressing with my finger I couldn&amp;#8217;t press it down. Still pressing with my fingernail, I could press it down, but it still didn&amp;#8217;t do anything. In slight despair at this point, I even asked an assistant for help. He kindly explained that device had crashed, force quit&amp;#8217;ed the hung application, and returned it to the home screen. I didn&amp;#8217;t catch what he did, even though I was looking. He asked if I would like further information. I said thanks, but I&amp;#8217;d seen enough…and walked away&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, with no agenda, looking for iPad alternatives; all the ones I tried offered a bad experience. Maybe I missed the good ones, but after trying three...I walked away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Hooray! Hooray! Minimum font size of incoming OS X Mail emails</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/12/22/hooray-hooray-minimum-font-size-of"/>
			<updated>2011-12-22T18:06:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/12/22/hooray-hooray-minimum-font-size-of</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stop being crippled by those silly micro-fonts from crap html email or one of several not-mentioned email clients, you know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hit the terminal with:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;defaults write com.apple.mail MinimumHTMLFontSize 12&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Thomas Reed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://discussions.apple.com/thread/1942517?start=0&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Apple Discussion Forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>TIP: Livescribe Smart Pen - rename your pen as your phone number</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/12/15/tip-livescribe-smart-pen-rename-your"/>
			<updated>2011-12-15T19:07:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/12/15/tip-livescribe-smart-pen-rename-your</id>
			<content type="html">
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Livescribe Echo Smartpen Review</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/12/07/livescribe-echo-smartpen-review"/>
			<updated>2011-12-07T15:36:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/12/07/livescribe-echo-smartpen-review</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using this &lt;em&gt;smartpen&lt;/em&gt; for a few weeks now and its a great toy. More than that, it closes the loop on the last spoke of that tough to fix &lt;em&gt;get it all digital and searchable&lt;/em&gt; wheel. So, what is a smartpen? Well, essentially, its a paper and ink writing tool which uses &lt;em&gt;special&lt;/em&gt; paper and a small camera in the end of the pen to digitise your scribblings, while optionally recording &lt;em&gt;and linking&lt;/em&gt; audio to the text, for transfer to your computer for storage and further processing.&lt;br /&gt;I got the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livescribe.com&quot;&gt;Livescribe&lt;/a&gt; Echo 2Gb, and this was a good choice for my needs. There are several component to making this smartpen part of your daily routine. I&amp;#8217;ll go through them one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Pen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The actual pen is pretty good, but not great as a design. I was anxious that it would be too chunky, but actually its pretty comfortable in my, admittedly large&amp;#8217;ish, male hands. Aesthetically, looking at the pen from the side, it has a nicely gentle vaguely-elliptical shape. Its pleasing to view. From the top, less so. In order to fit a headphone (and stereo microphone jacks) socket and micro-usb (for charging and sync&amp;#8217;ing) the pen is slightly spoilt for me, as it flares at the top. I believe the 4Gb and 8Gb models have a rubberised grip area, the 2Gb doesn&amp;#8217;t. I&amp;#8217;d imagine that it would be nice, but its not a show-stopper and you probably add 50% or more to the price of the pen for that and a few other &lt;em&gt;minor&lt;/em&gt; (for me) upgrades. I couldn&amp;#8217;t stomach that when I wasn&amp;#8217;t sure that I&amp;#8217;d make good use of the pen. The cap, it plain, awful. Its fine when on, but very difficult to get off. My hand strength is pretty good, I climb rocks for a hobby, but the pen lid required too much effort to get off. After struggling to get my nails under it, I&amp;#8217;ve figured out there is a trick to push the lid forward and backward first, which makes it easier to remove. Its very easy to lose, I&amp;#8217;m just waiting for this to happen. The pen is missing a clip too, I&amp;#8217;ve ended up chucking it in my bags, where it rattles around, that&amp;#8217;s a niggle. The fit and finish is okay, some of the seams on my model were a little misaligned with rough&amp;#8217;ish, sharp&amp;#8217;ish edges, and the top is a bit creaky. Its certainly not bad, but for an expensive pen, I hoped for some tighter control over manufacturing. Perhaps, I&amp;#8217;m just over fussy and too used to Apple hardware standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To make the Smartpen work, the camera picks up on tiny light blue dots on the &lt;em&gt;Livescribe Paper&lt;/em&gt; to locate the ink &amp;amp; pen&amp;#8217;s position. You get a tiny, selection of notelets when you buy the pen, but you&amp;#8217;re going to need some more if you get one. I ended up getting a two-pack of A5 Journal pads. These are excellent, they feel like high quality notebooks. The extra bonus, is that if you have a suitable printer (don&amp;#8217;t ask me what that means!) you can print your own paper, in booklets with, I think, 20 twenty pages or so at a go. I was a bit anxious that I&amp;#8217;d be committing to buying expensive proprietary paper to make this pen thing any use. This is a really nice fix, if you&amp;#8217;re in a fix. I&amp;#8217;d still recommend getting the pre-printed materials, but its really nice to have the option if you need some in a snap or for doodling while on your desk, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desktop Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Livescribe Desktop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Livescribe Desktop software is functional and fine. Once installed, which is pretty standard on OSX, sorry users on other platforms, don&amp;#8217;t know about them. It&amp;#8217;s a little counter-intuitive in that the audio recordings which synchronise with your writing (which is great) is displayed separately from the graphical renderings of your writings. &lt;br /&gt;The desktop application is the hub for doing stuff with the pen, for example, installing Apps, like Zork (which is, well, cool) or exporting to other places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Livescribe Connect&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This second application seems to need to run as well as the desktop application when you connect your pen to the computer. This seems a bit clumsy to me, but when you connect the pen via its usb cable, the Livescribe applications boot and sync. your recent data to the computer. The idea of the &lt;em&gt;Connect&lt;/em&gt; application, I think is a mechanism to set up tunnels to different locations for your &lt;em&gt;pencasts&lt;/em&gt;, e.g., Evernote, the desktop, email, or to google docs or sites. I should add, I&amp;#8217;ve played with this but not found it to be of much value. Some of the functionality is limited on the basic version and you need to pay to upgrade, which seems a bit cheap on a system like this. The fundamental shortcoming, I think, is that although you can use neat &lt;em&gt;while writing&lt;/em&gt; shortcuts to pipe your content to different places, you still need to connect the pen to the desktop to enable the process, and therefore you may as well just export the data when you at the desktop, the extra effort in minimal. Meh. Perhaps the next version will have Bluetooth or WiFi to enable remote sync&amp;#8217;ing, its got to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myscript&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the key components to getting your notes into your computer is linking it all together and making it searchable. There&amp;#8217;s a bit of a mystery here for me, in that Livescribe don&amp;#8217;t include, or even appear to own software to recognise handwriting and convert it to text. The Livescribe app store does link to &lt;em&gt;Myscript&lt;/em&gt; an option add on to convert and export your scrawl to searchable, and editable text. This seems, obviously to me something that should be included from the get go. In use, Myscript is pretty good. The UI is poor, obviously a quick and dirty Java port, but the functionality isn&amp;#8217;t bad at all. My writing is poor, and using the smartpen has encouraged me to try to make my script more legible, which does seem to help. However, the recognition isn&amp;#8217;t bad at all, and can be checked with the original pretty easily. You can also choose whether to export just text or formatted text, and or images too. A recommended buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s the practical experience of using the thing. The pre-printed paper provides some rather nice control for handedness, audio playback, volume, bookmarking, even a calculator, which works well. The standard pen refills are okay to write with, not great, but okay. More on that later. &lt;br /&gt;I&amp;#8217;m finding I need to retrain myself to reduce the number of unnecessary doodles to smooth the outputs to Myscript. In use, the controls are largely intuitive and well-thought out. I&amp;#8217;m still wrestling with a tidy way to manage separate documents or splitting notes, but one great thing about the system is that it just grabs all the stuff, and you can organise it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional Nerdology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A couple of minor drifts off into the unnecessary niceties. As mentioned above the standard pen refills are okay, a bit unrewarding to write with. A bit of digging and I found a &lt;a href=&quot;http://getsatisfaction.com/livescribe/topics/ink_refills_are_terrible&quot;&gt;forum post&lt;/a&gt; suggesting an alternative/better supplier, plus a bit of DIY. I opted for Gel refills from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cultpens.com&quot;&gt;Cult Pens&lt;/a&gt;. The closest gel refill for the Echo I&amp;#8217;ve found is the &amp;#8216;Zebra JSB Gel Refill 0.5mm&amp;#8217; at £4.07 each, ouch! These refills are tiny, and you need to cut them down to fit the pen too! Handily, the ink actually doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to reach up to the point you need to cut to. See the forum post for instructions, its pretty easy. Expensive, but better to write with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One nice feature is that you can use the pen on multiple machines, with a bit of care. Great for both desktop and laptop use. If you&amp;#8217;re weight-sensitive, you don&amp;#8217;t want to be carrying that huge cable with your lovely pen do you? &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.griffintechnology.com/usb-mini-cable-kit&quot;&gt;Griffin Technology&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue, with their &amp;#8216;USB Mini Cable Kit&amp;#8217;. Really nicely designed little cable-ettes, where you can take only what you need with you and not much else, they&amp;#8217;re great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Livescribe Echo Smartpen is a genuinely useful and interesting product. Its got its limitations, and some rabbit-holes of nerdery one can run down, but on balance, a good buy, especially the current entry model which can be picked up in the UK for around £80.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>The ultimate docking station</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/12/02/ultimate-docking-station"/>
			<updated>2011-12-02T17:37:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/12/02/ultimate-docking-station</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vr-zone.com/articles/intel-is-planning-docking-solution-for-next-year-s-ultrabooks-using-thunderbolt/14037.html&quot;&gt;VR Zone&lt;/a&gt; recently reported on a new Intel integrated docking solution, &amp;#8216;Common Housing Connector&amp;#8217; for the Ultrabooks. Franky, this is an ugly looking solution to an interesting problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.macrumors.com/article-new/2011/11/tb_dock_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Horrible design&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macrumors.com/2011/11/25/intel-working-on-standardized-thunderbolt-docking-system-for-pcs/&quot;&gt;MacRumors&lt;/a&gt; discusses this mentioning the Apple solution, the &amp;#8216;ultimate docking station&amp;#8217;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.macrumors.com/article-new/2011/07/dock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Slightly less horrible design&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Bah, this is an aesthetic, ergonomic mess. Any guesses why the single cable, with bifocating tendrils ended up that way. I&amp;#8217;d put my money on a nasty compromise between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a fudge on the Thunderbolt cable to stuff electronics in the (horrifically, suspiciously expensive) cable rather than the devices its connected to; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the rather nice, but arkwardly directional Magsafe connnector. Ironically, the old design would have worked better, as both &lt;em&gt;legs&lt;/em&gt; would be, at least, pointing the same way. The ergonomic problem these and many other &amp;#8216;straight out&amp;#8217; cables introduces is that they block the space where a mouse or paperwork should be able to comfortably operate constraining the user&amp;#8217;s workspace, not good. Oh, for the 90° usb cable adapter! But that&#39;s another story.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pangea.stanford.edu/~schmitt/magsafe/magsafe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Pub Rules</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/11/24/pub-rules"/>
			<updated>2011-11-24T09:53:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/11/24/pub-rules</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Advice on clear, concise, online communication:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Design for reading&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Design with little navigation&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Forget any “social media strategy”&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Include full text in RSS feed (and no ads)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Design for performance&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Make URLs human-readable&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Use responsive design techniques&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Allow a single analytics system&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Keep ads minimal&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Allow no Flash anywhere&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Make JavaScript optional and lightweight&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Never, ever, ever consider SEO&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;No custom URL shortener&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Consider a Newsstand app — eventually&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Great stuff, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/2011/11/23/pub_rules&quot;&gt;inessential.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Saying goodbye to paper</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/11/21/saying-goodbye-to-paper"/>
			<updated>2011-11-21T16:40:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/11/21/saying-goodbye-to-paper</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my university lecturers (from the early nineties) once said “the paperless office, is about as much use as a paperless toilet”. I’m largely in agreement, but in my quest to remove &lt;em&gt;unnecessary&lt;/em&gt; paperwork, I’ve invested in several bits of supporting technology. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In summary (with follow up posts as soon as time allows), and in order of anticipated usefulness:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a ScanSnap scanner. This is a neat form-feeding duplex scanner, modest desktop footprint and nicely slots into some of the other puzzle pieces, e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marinersoftware.com/products/paperless/&quot;&gt;Paperless&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smilesoftware.com/PDFpen/&quot;&gt;PDFPen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evernote.com/&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php&quot;&gt; Hazel&lt;/a&gt; and general handling of images and text. Hardware design is good, the software design is functional, if rather utilitarian and a bit, well, ugly.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a Livescribe ‘smart’ pen. I got the 2GB echo, which is an excellent gadget, for my use (I’m never far from a computer), I have no need of the four or eight GB editions.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Dragon Express, which I’m speaking this text with. It’s got a lot of promise, but v1.0 has its limitations, including a bug with Textexpander, and some other ‘error-beep’ bug, I can’t identify yet.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Social Engineering</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/11/18/someone-i-know-well-was-trying-to"/>
			<updated>2011-11-18T22:45:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/11/18/someone-i-know-well-was-trying-to</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;‘Someone I know well’ was trying to change a life insurance policy recently. An operator from the provider called to confirm some aspects of the policy. They opened the call by asking for the &lt;em&gt;name, address, and date of birth&lt;/em&gt; of the recipient of the call. To their credit, they hesitated, to respond “Hang on, you called me!” No information was offered by the caller to substantiate their identity until challenged. How many people will stop and think to ask for proof, and how many will give away their personal identification information? I’m guessing most. It seems like the assumption is that corporate representatives have the right to challenge their customers to prove their bonafides, without, in many cases, specifically taking efforts to do the same.Time for some balance in the service-client relationship. Perhaps, we should be asking more actively for proof of their identity or invoicing companies for time spent waiting in a telephone cue, hold on that’s a different story…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Measure Once, Cut Twice</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/11/18/really-liked-john-grubers-crafting"/>
			<updated>2011-11-18T22:27:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/11/18/really-liked-john-grubers-crafting</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Really liked John Gruber’s crafting analogy some time back about sensible and appropriate caution before action &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2011/05/measure_twice&quot;&gt;“Daring Fireball: Measure Twice, Cut Once”.&lt;/a&gt; Slightly saddened and concerned for the future about the reports online about battery performance getting worse from iOS 5.0.1. I hope 5.0.2 isn’t &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; quick getting released.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Discoverability</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/11/13/discoverability"/>
			<updated>2011-11-13T20:55:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/11/13/discoverability</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Someone I know well had noticed me using the iOS  5 notifications and started to ‘feel around’ to try to find this handy feature. I was fascinated/amused to see the other party making jumpy-uppy-downy finger spider impressions on the screen of their phone, while making a “shpliggity-splaggity” incantation to will the notification dialogue into existence. The user is in no way a novice iOS  user, but for them the control to initiate the desired interaction was completely invisible. It was a lovely example of a concern I have with touch-based interactions, the functionality is opaque. Its a key difference from the WIMP paradigm. The straightforward functions are readily point and draggable, but more subtle features are tough to predict or discover. Lovely, charming and whimsical when you find them, but no use for core funcationality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>iPhone SMS Auto-resend?</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/11/08/sms-auto-resend"/>
			<updated>2011-11-08T19:39:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/11/08/sms-auto-resend</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Come on iPhone, iOS 5 and still no SMS auto-resend on a failed attempt? My Nokia did this fifteen years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Great Customer Service [again]</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/11/06/great-customer-service-again"/>
			<updated>2011-11-06T22:18:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/11/06/great-customer-service-again</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On two separate occasions recently, I was trying to use apps, one on the iPhone and one on the Mac, and couldn’t find the functions I was looking for. One was a functional change in new version of the software (iCatcher!), while the other was the keyboard shortcut I couldn’t find (YoruFukurou). For both, I happened to try tweeting to the developers for advice, and on both occasions within an hour, I’d had quick and helpful replies solving my minor niggles. Just great, personal, helpful, human support. The world has changed and the small independent software developer is king (or Queen!)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Alerts, alerts, everywhere…but not where you want them</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/30/alerts-alerts-everywherebut-not-where"/>
			<updated>2011-10-30T12:55:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/30/alerts-alerts-everywherebut-not-where</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Feature request: harmonised, sync&#39;ed reminders and alerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminders and alerts in the Mac Universe are great in many ways. You can set an alarm for an event and no matter which device you&#39;re using you can be confident that you&#39;ll get that reminder; and there&#39;s the rub. If you have more than one &#39;integrated device&#39;, you get your alarm everywhere too, which can be a niggle if you have multiple Macs, iPhones, iPads, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets have an integrated, perhaps device prioritised mechanism for semi-intelligent alerts. When I acknowledge I&#39;ve &#39;cleared&#39; an alert on one device, I don&#39;t want it on &#39;all&#39; the others. Or at least, I&#39;d like the option to control that behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>AirServer for $5.59 - 30% off - MacUpdate Promo</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/28/airserver-for-559-30-off-macupdate"/>
			<updated>2011-10-28T13:04:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/28/airserver-for-559-30-off-macupdate</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a great app for streaming content to your Mac/s. I use it all the time to send podcasts, which I only download and keep on my iPhone, onto my MacBook Air (which is capacity challenged).  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Highly recommended.&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mupromo.com/deal/1668/7024/airserver&quot;&gt;MacUpdate Promo - AirServer 3.1.2 for $5.59 - 30% off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>ANY Lion Mail Search Token as the default?</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/25/why-default-from-lion-mail-search-token"/>
			<updated>2011-10-25T10:10:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/25/why-default-from-lion-mail-search-token</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lion search tokens are great, but why doesn’t it default to ‘ANY’?  If you’re in the Inbox, it will select From, if you’re in the Sent mail, it will default to To, but once I’ve found someone’s email, I’m often looking for the whole conversation not just half of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Positive, positive, positive…iterate, iterate, iterate</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/23/positive-positive-positiveiterate"/>
			<updated>2011-10-23T17:22:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/23/positive-positive-positiveiterate</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just reflecting on my current ramblings, and I think I might be coming across a little on the negative side. I’m interested in how we can improve the user experience and inherently, its easy to ‘pick holes’ where others have tried. Any truely successful design needs interation around the user’s needs, and that’s a predicable part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Terrifying Uncertainty</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/23/terrifying-uncertainty"/>
			<updated>2011-10-23T17:17:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/23/terrifying-uncertainty</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icloud.com/&quot;&gt;iCloud&lt;/a&gt; offers wonderful promise as a mechanism to free us all from the need to organise and manage our data. Unfortunately, the whole package isn’t there yet, and that’s a big problem for the users.  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We’re impoverished, in terms of documentation. For example, what it can do, what it can’t do; when it will work, and when it won’t work. That’s a lot of uncertainty, especially when core to the concept is storing our &lt;strong&gt;precious&lt;/strong&gt; data, and presumably without the need to worry about where and what it is. ‘Just all available everywhere, when you need it.’ That’s fine, if it is, but the current release, only really integrates the iOS devices, not the desktop. Now I appreciate that we’re &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; going to be getting more mobile, but, I’m guessing that most people still produce and manipulate most of their content (90% or more) on the desktop, and many spend most of their working day in front of a computer. Needing to use iTunes or a browser to access iCloud documents, just ain’t right. If iCloud is going to be of use, it needs to be integrated across devices, and either in a way that there is never any problem (not currently the case) or in a predictable or documented way.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Why would anyone use it now? You have to manage your documents to get them on or off the desktop, and then you can’t be sure you’ll have them available when you need them. So much more effort than, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dropbox.com&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s hope that its early-adopter pain, but why didn’t Apple hold off until all the pieces were in place, given the huge efforts they have clearly made.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>iOS5 iPad Split-Keyboard is Great, But Not for Humans</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/16/ios5-ipad-split-keyboard-is-great-but"/>
			<updated>2011-10-16T22:42:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/16/ios5-ipad-split-keyboard-is-great-but</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The iOS5 split keyboard on the iPad is an excellent option to enable two-handed thumb-typing, which works great on an iPhone. It’s just a little bit of a shame it was designed for aliens with thumbs below their little fingers. The anthropometry of the human hand would suggest the half keyboards were a bit higher up the screen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; fix for humans, the key is to press and hold the bottom-right keyboard button and then select ‘Undock’ before dragging the keyboard apart or selecting the ‘Split’ option.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Arghh! images from 3rd party photo apps don't get added to iOS 5 Photostream</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/16/arghh-images-from-3rd-party-photo-apps"/>
			<updated>2011-10-16T13:39:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/16/arghh-images-from-3rd-party-photo-apps</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A bit of initial testing, hope I’m wrong, but it looks like only the images collected by iOS apps get uploaded to the Photostream. The cutting of the cord, then makes it a right pain to get these orphans off the device. It no longer shows up in Aperture/iPhoto Image Capture. Using PhotoSync does the trick but you need to figure out what isn’t in the ‘stream’.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Can’t seem to see a way to actually import the Photostream images either. I wonder what happens to them after the 30 days/1000 images limits get exceeded?&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; you can drag images from the Photostream to an Aperture folder, etc (whew!). &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Server Busy?</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/15/server-busy"/>
			<updated>2011-10-15T10:15:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/15/server-busy</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;No surprises here and lots to say about this, but suffice to say, this made me a little nervous:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lh6.ggpht.com/-Dlqu-gdGD9M/TpnHGLDAH5I/AAAAAAAAABI/rBsQVFM4i4k/6245532521_5b95837ef5.jpg?imgmax=800&quot; alt=&quot;6245532521 5b95837ef5&quot; title=&quot;6245532521_5b95837ef5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;142&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Excellent OSX Screen Grab Summary</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/13/excellent-osx-screen-grab-summary"/>
			<updated>2011-10-13T12:27:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/13/excellent-osx-screen-grab-summary</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fosk.it/how-to-change-default-file-format-for-grabapp-on-os-x.html&quot;&gt;How to change default file format for Grab.app on OS X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>345</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/11/345"/>
			<updated>2011-10-11T13:08:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/11/345</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; some little task you do repetitively, you recognise this is a waste of your time, and you can think of how to streamline your workflow to reduce, remove or optimise the task.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choice:&lt;/strong&gt; do you:&lt;br /&gt;a) invest the effort to reduce, remove or optimise it, or &lt;br /&gt;b) live with the inefficiency knowing you’ve wasted no time on implementing a solution?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Approach:&lt;/strong&gt; Almost always, I will invest the time to optimise now, for the long term fix. When I find myself doing this kind of thing, I coming round to thinking of the behavior as a ‘345’. Three hours of work in one sitting, for five minutes of daily benefit. On balance, I think this is good plan, but I do realise that the system has its productivity weaknesses, that need some careful consideration before creating a 345 or not.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;how long will the tweak actually take? It’s &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; longer than you think.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;how often do you actually do this five minute task?&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;can you remember your fix if too much time passes before you use it again?&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;is it going to be &lt;em&gt;resistant&lt;/em&gt; to task changes?&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Too many walls in my walled garden</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/11/too-many-walls-in-my-walled-garden"/>
			<updated>2011-10-11T11:16:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/11/too-many-walls-in-my-walled-garden</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, I knew I’d have a few hours free while on the move so I thought I’d rent a Film from iTunes (hey, why not!). Downloaded the movie to a Mac at home. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fail 1. &lt;/strong&gt;Home sharing is on on all my machines, no sign of the download on my iPad or the machine I sync with the it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Copied it to the Mac I sync with my iPad, selected the option to move it to the iPad from iTunes, with the peculiarly-required Internet connection in place. The clock is now ticking as I needed to get moving with my day, weird I know. Sync’ed the iPad, anticipation of my investment in cinematic joy in store. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fail 2. &lt;/strong&gt;iTunes tells me the film won’t sync because it’s been moved. Bah.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a user I’m not seeking to copy or steal content, I’d just like to view the film I’ve rented. I invested in the end to end product, Apple hardware and software ‘tightly integrated’ to provide. Seamless user experience. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I guess I’ll just buy a DVD next time and use Handbrake, which, of course, is excellent.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Fantastical Greyscale Menu Bar Icon</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/08/fantastical-greyscale-menu-bar-icon"/>
			<updated>2011-10-08T23:09:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/08/fantastical-greyscale-menu-bar-icon</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;[http://flexibits.com/fantastical]&quot;&gt;Fantastical&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool, but the problem with being really good in so many ways, is that it raises the bar; and then I bother to get niggled by the tiny little things. For example, the one colour menu bar icon in my menu: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;colourmenu&quot; src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6233/6223715719_7010d5502b_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;colourmenu&quot; title=&quot;colourmenu&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So a quick bit of hacking around with a couple of .png files in the application Package (if you don’t know what that is, don’t think about this), and voilà: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;greymenu&quot; src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6234/6223715651_54d9d3fd52_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;greymenu&quot; title=&quot;greymenu&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Greyscale and calm restored to the menubar. These are the image files if you’d like them. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;statusitemcolor&quot; src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6153/6224401918_4d626e8f9d_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;StatusItemColor&quot; title=&quot;StatusItemColor&quot; /&gt; StatusItemColor.png and &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;statusitemcolormonth&quot; src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6105/6223882143_aaff3cbb8f_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;StatusItemColorMonth&quot; title=&quot;StatusItemColorMonth&quot; /&gt; StatusItemColorMonth.png &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These are .jpg’s, save them as .png’s with the same name and overwrite the originals.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; in version 1.1 there’s now an option for a black and white icon, yay!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>iPad Keyboard Weirdness/Niggles...</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/08/ipad-keyboard-weirdnessniggles"/>
			<updated>2011-10-08T19:20:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/08/ipad-keyboard-weirdnessniggles</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay, so why do keys jump around when you use the &#39;?123&#39; modifier? I&#39;m talking to you Mr question mark and Mr exclamation, among others!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6044/6223518507_ab56f88ec7.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6044/6223518507_ab56f88ec7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6218/6223518503_9bb270b745.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6218/6223518503_9bb270b745.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>A New Place for my Thoughts</title>
			<link href="http://terrylansdown.github.io/posts/2011/10/08/this-blog-is-here-for-my-ramblings"/>
			<updated>2011-10-08T18:22:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://terrylansdown.github.io//posts/2011/10/08/this-blog-is-here-for-my-ramblings</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog is here for my ramblings about usability, design and human factors. Getting the format and structure right, well not too terrible has been a good example, for me, of the challenges of resisting OCD, while setting up a stucture I’m happy with. In other words, hours of fiddling about for initally very little obvious benefit. Hopefully, the user interface supports focus on the important bit, what I’m thinking about, without getting in your face.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lunacy over the details, which I hope to write about as the time goes by. For example,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;favicons&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;navigation, and getting back to the home screen&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;cutting out all the css crap&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;fading the non-focus items into the background&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;working up a workflow, and yes, trying out the presumed efficiencies from multi-markdown writing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;twitter integration (work in progress)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	

</feed>
